Contact

sansyrox@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/sanskar123 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Python (Programming Language)
Node.js
C++

Languages

English (Native or Bilingual) Hindi (Native or Bilingual)

Honors-Awards

Facebook F8 Scholarship
OpenTechNights'19 Winner
OpenTechNights'18 Winner

Publications

Bypassing Tinder's Premium Model

Sanskar Jethi

Major League Hacking Fellow | Research Intern at IIITD | Incoming PE Intern @Facebook | Placement Coordinator at Delhi Technological University (Formerly DCE)

East Delhi

Summary

I am a Senior year student at Delhi Technological University. I have been a developer ever since I was 12 years of age who is an Open Source enthusiast and a coding fanatic. I am deeply passionate about software development and to work with extremely talented people to collaborate and make products that would make an immediate impact. I enjoy hacking things up for any immediate problems or projects I want to pursue. For example, I spotted an oligopoly of premium music service providers, I immediately created a web app to solve this issue for good. I always have a holistic approach while building an app. I do not get obsessed by a single aspect of the app, rather I wear multiple hats until I am able to ship a product.

Most of my personal projects always come from a problem I want to solve, and it is by solving that problem that I grow and develop my coding abilities. I always break down the problem into smaller pieces and work my way up using learning the necessary tools to complete it. I have excellent work ethics and I enjoy solving difficult challenges and learning from them.

I served as a Teaching Assistant at Stanford University for CS108a in 2020, Google Summer of Code Intern in 2018 and a Mentor in 2020 as well. I work part-time as a Full Stack Developer at FOSSASIA and a Full Stack Mentor at Udacity.

Being well versed in API architecture and security, it makes a complete Full Stack Developer. I recently had a publication(https://apisecurity.io/issue-41-tinder-and-axway-breached-equifax-fined/) on finding a significant vulnerability in Tinder's main API and bypassing their only premium model. I have also won various scholarships, including the scholarship to Facebook F8 hackathon and conference. I have also given talks at various national and international conferences.

Experience

Major League Hacking MLH Fellow May 2020 - Present (4 months)

- Part of the inaugural class of MLH Fellows (powered by GitHub & Facebook).
- Contributed to Open Source projects written in JavaScript with a focus on React & the React ecosystem with a team of Fellows under the educational mentorship of a professional software engineer.
- Contributed to React Native Core which is an Open Source Cross-Platform Mobile Development Framework by Facebook.

Delhi Technological University (Formerly DCE)
Placement Coordinator
June 2020 - Present (3 months)
Placement Coordinator for the session 2020-21.

FOSSASIA

Full Stack Engineer September 2018 - Present (2 years)

Indraprastha Institute of Information Technology, Delhi Research Intern @ CoSy Labs May 2020 - July 2020 (3 months)

- Researched under Prof. Ganesh Baglar
- Created cross-platform apps to explore the field of Computational Gastronomy.

Udacity

1 year

Mentor - Java Development August 2019 - March 2020 (8 months)

Mentor - Full Stack Development April 2019 - March 2020 (1 year)

Google Summer of Code

Full Stack Engineer | FOSSASIA April 2018 - August 2018 (5 months)

Fossasia, Singapore

Education

Delhi College of Engineering
Bachelor of Technology - BTech · (2017 - 2021)

Delhi Public School - R. K. Puram (2015 - 2017)

Delhi Public School Noida · (2003 - 2015)